If I wanted to go from white belt to blue belt as fast as I possibly could,
he's exactly what I would do.
I changed gyms and telomells already at blue belt.
No, please don't fucking do that.
I've heard of people doing that.
It's a very bad idea.
What I would actually do is in the first three months of my training,
I would heavily prioritize bottom position escapes.
Now that means things like north south side control, mount, half guard,
and you could even include the back in this one.
The bulk of your training in the first three months is going to be defending
and surviving in these positions.
If you want to speed that up, select two escapes from each of those positions
and make sure that you use them in conjunction with each other,
not just as random pieces you throw and hope work.
The next biggest problem that you need to solve that you're going to face
in your training as a white belt is actually starting to use offense
off the back of those escapes.
So many times I get asked the question,
oh, well, I escaped, so I controlled there to spin to north south.
What should I do?
We should start to fire off things like wrestling up or submission threats
so that you can actually stop your partner from just moving forwards
and get them to consider that you might be offering some sort of danger
and give you an opportunity to then turn the tide.
Once you turn the tide with offense,
you now need to reverse engineer all the things that you learn in the
pin escapes phase to start to pin your opponent on the floor.
It's all well and good if you can sweep them and threaten them with submissions
or wrestle up.
But if you can't keep them there, you've wasted your time.
Then and only then do you have the permission to focus on submissions
because if you can't escape from bottom position,
you can't generate offense, you can't pin your training partner.
The amount of subs that you're going to get is very limited anyway.
Position always precedes submission.
And until you learn that, you're not going to be getting many of them.
And the ones that you do get are going to be hail Mary's.
And if you want to be doing the sport for a long time to a high degree of quality,
you don't want to rely on hail Mary's.
And after you've pinned your training partner,
then you can start to isolate limbs and cruise to a submission finish.
If you can do all that reliably to a variety of training partners,
as a white belt, I dare say you're very close to a blue belt.